Guide to the Andrew Wellington Cordier Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series V:The United Nations Period And Related Files
  - Subseries V.4: The Secretaries General
    - Sub-subseries V.4.2:Dag Hammarskjold 1953-1961
      - Following list includes. trips on which no file exists: (Box 117)
        - 1958
          - *(RESTRICTED) Stockholm; Moscow, Geneva, London (addressed House of Parliament in London; also UNA), 21 Mar-5 Apr 1958 (Reporting letters, cables, telex,; also Folder of press clippings, press releases, mementos of program re visits) (Box 119)
          - Washington D.C., 15-16 April 1958 (*No file) (Box 119)
          - *(RESTRICTED) Geneva, via Brussels and Paris, 3-10 May 1958 (Reporting cables and telex; itinerary) (Box 119)
          - Miami, 19-20 May 1958 (Governors' Conference itinerary, correspondence) (Box 119)
          - Oslo, London, Cambridge, 31 May-6 Jun 1958 (Reporting cables texts of speeches Cambridge Univ and UNA, Oslo) (Box 120)
          - London, Beirut (?), 17-28 June 1958 (*Nothing on file exce program in Brussels 25-27 June 1958. Was trip cancelled?) (Box 120)
          - Washington, 7 July 1958 (*No file) (Box 120)
          - *(RESTRICTED) Middle East and Europe: (Geneva, Beirut, Cairo, Amman, Jerusalem), 25 Aug-13 September 1958 (Itinerary; reporting cables; and letters; press and press release) (Box 120)
          - *(RESTRICTED) Middle East and Africa: (Stockholm, Beirut,Gaza (for Xmas), Khartoum, Addis Ababa, Mogadiscio, Amnan, Ruyadh, Cairo, Benghazi), 18 Dec-9 January 1958 (Itinerary; reporting cables; press releases) (Box 120)
        - 1959 (see above)
          - Washington, 17-18 January 1959 (*No file) (Box 120)
          - Nassau (Andros Island), 20-25 January 1959 (Itinerary; reporting cables) (Box 120)
          - *(RESTRICTED) Subcontinent, S.E. Asia, Eastern Europe (Karachi, Rangoon, Bangkok, Vientiane, Phnom Penh, Kuala Lumpur, Kathmandu, New Delhi, Kabul, Moscow), 28 February-29 March 1959 (Reporting cables and letters; draft itineraries; spares) (Box 120)
          - Mexico 6-9 April 1959 (Correspondence and cables re. arrangements—speech text) (Box 120)
          - *(RESTRICTED) Copenhagen, Lund, Malmo, Stockholm, Geneva, Caracas, Panama, New York (Foreign Ministers' conGeneva), 1-15 May 1959 (Itinerary, press releases, reporting cables) (Box 120)
          - Washington, 1-15 May 1959 (Itinerary) (Box 120)
          - Washington, 27 May 1959 (*No file. Dulles’ funeral) (Box 120)
          - *(RESTRICTED) Latin America (Buenos Aires, Asuncion, Montevideo, Rio de Janeiro), 23 Aug-6 Sep 1959 (Itinerary, reporting cables &letters, press releases) (Box 121)
          - *(RESTRICTED) Vientiane (Laos), 10-21 November 1959, 1960 (includes December 1959) (Itinerary, reporting cables) (Box 121)
          - *(RESTRICTED) "Africa" trip: (Stockholm, Paris, Lisbon, Dakar, Monrovia, Conakry (Xmas), Accra, Lome, Lagos & Kaduna, Yaounde, Tiko, U Brazzaville, Leopoldville, Usumbura, Dar es Salaam, Zanzibar, Nairobi, Entebhe, Mogadiscio, Addis Abba, Khartoum, Cairo, Tunis, Rabat, Tangier, Madrid), 18-Dec -31 Jan 1960 –(Itinerary, reporting cables; working Folder with -separate files on arrangements; working Folder with separate files on countries visited; Folder of background papers) (Box 121)
          - Stockholm, Copenhagen, 25-29 February 1960 (Itinerary, reporting cables, press release) (Box 122)
          - Washington, 8 March 1960 (Itinerary and press release) (Box 122)
          - Nassau (Andros Island), 16-22 March 1960 (Itinerary, reporting cables & re arrangements, press release) (Box 122)
          - *(RESTRICTED) Geneva (re disarmament mtgs), 26-30 Apr 1960 (Itinerary, reporting cables) (Box 122)
          - Chicago, 1-2 May 1960 (No file) (Box 122)
          - *(RESTRICTED) London (for talks with officials of Union of South Africa), 12-17 May 1960 (Itinerary, press release, reporting. cables) (Box 122)
          - Geneva, 8-11 July 1960 (Itinerary, press release, reporting cables) (Box 122)
          - *(RESTRICTED) Brussels, Leopoldville, 26 Jul-6 Aug 1960 (?) (Itinerary, press releases, cables) (Box 122)
          - Leopoldville, 11-16 August 1960 (No file) (Box 122)
        - 1961
          - *(RESTRICTED) Pretoria, Johannesburg (via Leopoldville) 4-13 January 1961 (Itinerary, reporting cables, press release) (Box 122)
          - London (degree from Oxford), 29 May-l June 1961 (No file) (Box 122)
          - *(RESTRICTED) Geneva, 8-15 July 1961 (Itinerary, reporting cables) (Box 122)
          - Tunis, Bizerte, 23-27 July 1961 (Reporting cables) (Box 122)
          - Leopoldville/Ndo1a via Accra, 12-17 September 1961 (air crash 17/9/61) (LAST TRIP. No file made. See Congo codes & clears for a cables) (Box 122)
      - Miscellaneous: (Box 123)
        - DH Aides-Memoire, covering period April 1953 -February 1954 (private DH papers -­returned to Swedish custody c/o Peder Hammarskjold) DG (Box 123)
        - Appointment as Secretary General 1953 (& second term) (Box 123)
        - Biographical material (Box 123)
        - Cambridge Univ. (hon. degree) (Box 123)
        - Estate matters (Box 123)
        - Bo Hammarskjold, correspondence (Box 123)
        - Nobel Peace Prize (Box 123)
        - Photo--grave, Uppsala (Box 123)
        - Photos, residence and office (posthumous) (Box 123)
        - Photos, self (Box 123)
        - Private papers & files: correspondence re. disposition after decease (1961) (Box 123)
        - Profiles and Tributes (Box 123)
        - Publication in Swedish of DH statements (Box 123)
        - UN concerts arranged by Mr. Hammarskjold (Box 123)
        - Speeches, University & introductions to annual reports:(List) (Box 123)
      - Air Crash:
        - Telex conversations (Box 123)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Cables
          - Condolences: (Box 124)
            - Heads of state, perm reps, other govt. officials (Box 124)
            - Individuals, groups (Box 124)
            - Individuals, replies sent (Box 124)
            - Organizations (Box 124)
            - Press releases (Box 124)
            - Statements, Member Countries (Box 124)
      - Deceased staff members:
        - Compensation to dependents (Box 124)
        - Personal effects (Box 124)
        - Transport of deceased (Box 124)
        - Next of kin (Box 124)
        - Barrau (Box 124)
        - Eivers (Box 124)
        - Fabry (Box 124)
        - H. Julien (Box 124)
        - Lalande (Box 124)
        - Ranallo (Box 124)
        - Wieschchoff (Box 124)
      - Investigation: (Box 125)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Cables (Box 125)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Miscellaneous:
          - Investigation by Govt. Rhodesia.and Nyasaland (Box 125)
          - Photographs (Box 125)
          - Spinelli (Box 125)
          - UN Observers report (Box 125)
          - UN Commission report (Box 125)
          - UN Commission hearings (Box 125)
        - Memorial services:
          - DR funeral, Uppsala, 29 September 1961 (Box 125)
          - General Assembly 29 September 1961, (3 Folders) (Box 125)
          - Idlewild ceremony, 30 September 1961 (Box 125)
          - Religious groups (Box 125)
          - Westminster Abbey (Box 125)
          - UNESCO (Box 125)
        - Memorials: (Box 126)
          - DH memorials, general file (Box 126)
          - DR memorials, suggestions for (Box 126)
          - DH memorials, Amherst College (Box 126)
          - DH memorials, Association of the Bar (NY State) (Box 126)
          - DR memorials, J. Blaustein (Single Form) (Box 126)
          - DH memorials, City of New York (Box 126)
          - DH memorials, N. Y. State (Box 126)
          - DH memorials, Parvil Foundation (Box 126)
          - California, State of (Box 126)
          - Secretariat News (memorial issues) (Box 126)
          - UN Staff Association (Box 126)
          - H. Wieschhoff memorial (Box 126)
          - Brewster, NY—"landmark" house (1973) (Box 126)
        - Tributes:
          - G/A Sixteenth session (Box 126)
          - Com. On SW Africa Blaustein (Box 126)
          - Cordier (Box 126)
          - Flags (Box 126)
          - Lash (Box 126)
          - Lerner (Box 126)
          - Radio programs (Box 126)
          - Registers (Box 126)
          - Seattle World's Fair (Box 126)
          - Secretariat News (Box 126)
          - Secretariat Personnel (Box 126)
          - Under-Secretaries (Box 126)
          - Miscellaneous clippings and articles (not sorted) (Box 127-128)
    - Sub-subseries V.4.3: Secretary-General Files
      Files which were periodically turned over to Mr. Cordier to keep in his office by Mr. Lie or Mr. Hammarskjold or matters of concern to the S.G.)
      - Advisory Conunittce on Administrative and Budgetary Questions (letters, memos, etc.) (l947-1953) (Box 129)
      - Atomic Energy (correspondence, memos, etc. 1949-1955) (Box 129)
      - Berlin Question 1948 (reports and correspondence) (Box 129)
      - Balkan Question 1946-1951 (Memos, cables, background papers) (Box 129)
      - Casa1s, Pablo (Invitation to participate UN concert: complaint by Spain) 1958 (Box 129)
      - Cuba 1960 Conference of Underdeveloped countries, request for assistance (Box 129)
      - *(RESTRICTED) East-West Relations, resumption of (correspondence, papers, 1950-58) (Box 129)
      - Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Pres USA 1952-1958) SG correspondence with (Box 129)
      - Evatt, Herbert, Pres. 3rd Session General Assembly 1948-1949 (Sg correspondence with) (Box 129)
      - Gross, Ernest, correspondence, 1953-1958 (Box 130)
      - Houdek, Vladimir (asylum USA) 1950. Correspondence, statement (Box 130)
      - Holy See, relations with: Correspondence, memos 1957 (Box 130)
      - Legal Aspects of Office of Secretary General (memo and study 1959) (Box 130)
      - Lie, Trygve:
        - Resignation from United Nations 1952 (Box 130)
        - Twenty Year Peace Plan (1950-1951) (Box 130)
      - Mindszenty, Cardinal (legal issues) 1949 (Box 130)
      - Jackson, Robert (Asst. Sec. Gen 1948) Correspondence, memos, etc. 1948-1949 (Box 130)
      - Ording re. UN Appeal for Children (UNAC), 1948 (Box 130)
      - Owen, David, 1 letter 1949 (Box 130)
      - Pelt, Adrian 1951 (Box 130)
      - Pound, Ezra (SG letters re status 1957) (Box 130)
      - Protocol Status of the Secretary-General (Box 130)
      - Schuman, Robert (Public Info. on the UN in Europe; consultations & study 1954-55) (Box 131)
      - Schwebel, Stephen (Thesis on the SG: 1950) (Box 131)
      - Stevenson, Adlai (correspondence, 1952 SG) (Box 131)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Top level posts (correspondence re candidates, 1946-1961) (Box 131)
      - Truman, Harry S., correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 131)
      - *(RESTRICTED) "Typewriter case" (Liebmann Breweries), 1960 (Box 131)
      - US Public Opinion and the United Nations (correspondence lie study 1953-1958) (Box 131)
      - Van Kleffens, Eelco, President 9th session G/A (bio sketch) (Box 131)
      - World Brotherhood (study of international issues 1958) (Box 131)
  - Subseries V.5: Subject Files
    - Sub-subseries V.5.1: Asia
      - China: (Box 132)
        - Release of American POW's: Hammarskjold-Chou meetings January 1955 (copy) (Box 132)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Representation at United Nations: correspondence, memos, etc. 1949-1961 (includes visit of People's Republic delegation to UN in 1950) (Box 132)
        - International Review Service (Box 132)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Bangkok: code cables, 1960-1962 (Box 132)
      - Geneva Conference on Asian Problems, 1954 (arrangements, reporting, etc. Geneva office (Box 132)
      - *(RESTRICTED) India-Pakistan Military Observer Group (UNMOGIP) Cables, 1961-1962 (Box 132)
      - Korea: (not very complete)—see also China representation file:
        - Cease fire and armistice (Box 132)
        - General file of correspondence, memos, drafts (Box 132)
        - Countries contributing military and other assistance (Box 132)
        - Documentation (Box 132)
        - Peace Delegations at UN (Box 132)
        - Press Releases (UN, other) (Box 132)
        - UNCURK (Box 132)
        - Unified Command (Box 132)
      - *(RESTRICTED) UNKOR cables, 1961-1962 (*UNKOR?) (Box 133)
      - Japan-Korea negotiations (SG FILE) (Japan) (Box 133)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Thailand-Cambodia, correspondence, memos, etc., 1960-1962 (SG FILE) (Box 133)
      - Laos:
        - *(RESTRICTED) 14 Power conference, Geneva, May 1961 (Box 133)
        - Documents (Security Council, September 1959) (Box 133)
        - *(RESTRICTED) General correspondence file, 1958-1961 (Box 133)
        - Heurtematte Report (technical assistance) (Box 133)
        - Press Releases, 1959-1961 (Box 133)
        - Security Council Sub-Committee mtgs, 1959 (Box 134)
        - State Department, Reports: Situation in Laos, November 1959 (Box 134)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Tuomioja Report, Economic conditions in Laos, December 1959 (Box 134)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Code Cables, 1959-1960 (Box 134)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Code Cables, 1962-1962 (Box 134)
        - Clear Cables, 1959-1960 (Box 134)
        - Clear Cables, 1960-1962 (Box 134)
    - Sub-subseries V.5.2: Africa-General
      - Background papers, documents, cables 1960 (new memberships) (Box 135)
      - African States Conferences, 1960-1962 press releases (Box 135)
      - Algeria: Algerian Front of National Liberation (1 memo) (Box 135)
      - Angola situation:
        - *(RESTRICTED) Cables, 1961 (Box 135)
        - Correspondence, memos 1961 (Box 135)
        - Documents, 1961-62 (Box 135)
        - Press Releases, 1961 (Box 135)
      - Buraimi, 1 memo 1961 (SG FILE) (Box 135)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Camerouns (UN Plebiscite 1961), cables, correspondence (Box 135)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Somalia—independence:
        - UN Mission, general file 1960-1961 (Box 135)
        - UN Mission, cables 1960-61 (Box 135)
      - South Africa (Sharpville incident March 1960): (Box 136)
        - Correspondence and background papers (Box 136)
        - Security Council documents 1960-1961 (Box 136)
        - Secretary-General's discussions with South African Govt., 1960-1961 (Box 136)
      - South West Africa:
        - UN Commission on South West Africa: correspondence, etc. 1959-1961 (Box 136)
        - *(RESTRICTED) UN Commission on South West Africa:. cables 1961 (Box 136)
        - Documents, 1959-1961
          - UN Good Offices Commission (Box 136)
          - UN Commission on: SW Africa (Box 136)
      - Guinea (Special Representative, SG):
        - *(RESTRICTED) Cables, 1959-1961 (Box 136)
        - Communications with Government 1959 (Box 136)
        - Minutes of meeting at Hq. 13 July 1959 (Box 136)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Pelt appt. as Special Representative (Box 136)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Pelt reports and correspondence (May-December 1959) (Box 136)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Rosenborg (Successor to Pelt) Reports December 1959-Dec 1960 (Box 137)
        - Miscellaneous working papers (Box 137)
        - Press releases (Box 137)
      - Ruanda-Urundi:
        - Information Centre, creation of 1961 (Box 137)
        - Press Releases, 1961 (Box 137)
        - *(RESTRICTED) UN Economic Commission to Ruand-Urundi, 1960 (Box 137)
        - UN Commission to Ruanda-Urundi, 1961
          - Administrative arrangements (Box 137)
          - *(RESTRICTED) Cables, code (Box 137)
          - Cables, clear (Box 137)
          - Commission Secretariat: Evans reporting letters (Box 137)
          - Governments, correspondence with (Box 137)
          - General Assembly documents, 1960-1961 (Box 138)
      - Togoland (Independence 1960) (Secretary-General's Representative):
        - *(RESTRICTED) Cables, 1960-1961 (Box 138)
        - Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 138)
        - Documents, 1960 (Box 138)
        - Press Releases, 1960 (Box 138)
      - Tunisia -France 1961
        - Cordier aides-memoire re discussions with US (CONFIDENTIAL) (Box 138)
        - Security Council: S/documents (Box 139)
        - General Assembly,(Third Special Scssion):
          - A/documents (Box 139)
          - Press Releases (Box 139)
          - Request for special session (Box 139)
    - Sub-subseries V.5.3: Africa-Congo
      - Press Releases: (Box 140)
        - BIOS CO Series 1-190 (includes c0 -Chronological Background) (Box 140)
        - Notes to Correspondents, Aug 1960 -Feb 1962 (Box 140)
        - PM series (miscellaneous), Sep 1960-Mar 1961 (Box 140)
        - SG series 933-1145 (statements, announcements, etc.) (Box 140)
        - Secretary General Press Conferences, 1961,.Acting Secretary-General & Bunche (Box 140)
      - Documentation: (Box 141)
        - Lists of General Assembly (A) and Security Council (S) documents (Box 141)
        - Security Council documents: S/
          - S/Agenda, July 1960-Dec 1961 (Box 141)
          - Reports by Secretary General, July 1960-Dec 1961 (plus two of 1963) (Box 141)
          - Reports from Secretary-General's Representative, Aug 1960-1963 (Box 142)
          - S/ resolutions, July 1960-Nov 1961 (Box 142)
          - S/documents other than reports and resolutions: July 1960-May 1963 (Box 143)
          - S/verbatims, July 1960-Jan 1962 & Oct 1963 (to 14 September 1960) (Box 143)
          - (14 September 1960 -February 1961) (Box 144)
          - (November 1961 -1963) (Box 145)
      - Documentation:
        - General Assembly documents: A/:
          - A/resolutions, Sep 1960-Apr 1961 (to November 1960) (Box 145)
          - A/verbatims Sep 1960-Apr 1961 (November 1960-April 1961 April, 1961 (Box 146)
          - A/documents other than reports, resolutions, Jul 1960-Dec 1961 & Oct 1963 (Box 147)
          - 15th session A/documents, Fifth Committee (Costs and Financing) (Box 147)
          - Resumed 15th session: extracts from statements by representatives (Box 147)
      - Cables: Clear cables, Jul-Sep 1960 (Volumes I-V) (Box 148-156)
      - Clear cables, Oct 1960-Feb 1962 (Volumes VI-XXVI) (Box 148-156)
      - Advisory Committee (correspondence, misc. papers) (For verbatims of mtgs. see Drawer #4) (Box 157)
      - Conciliation Commission:
        - *(RESTRICTED) Cables (Box 157)
        - Documents --CC series, Jan-Feb 1961 (Box 157)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 157)
        - Protitch (Leopo1dvi11e), correspondence (Box 157)
        - CC Report to General Assembly' (Doc. A471l) and addenda (Box 157)
        - Reports from F.T. Liu (Leopoldville) (Box 157)
        - CC Summary Records, 1960-1961 (Box 157)
      - Civilian Operations: (Box 158)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 158)
        - Personnel list (Box 158)
        - Progress Reports (Box 158)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Vegega memos (Box 158)
      - Miscellaneous Files:
        - African Group meetings (Box 158)
        - Agricultural Technical Assistance Foundation (Box 158)
        - Background papers (Box 159)
        - Bases, Kitona and Kamina (Box 159)
        - Communiques (Box 159)
        - "Congo Lessons" Report to SG on the UN Force from General Von Horn (to December 1960) (Box 159)
        - Coquilhatville. Conference (Box 159)
        - Dayal (Box 159)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Financial Arrangements (Box 159)
        - Fundamental Law (Loi Fondamentale) (Box 159)
        - *(RESTRICTED) General file (memos, letters, cables, reports) (Box 160)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Guinea (UN Office) (Box 160)
        - Kasavubu (Box 160)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Katanga (Box 160)
        - Katanga: Documents (Box 161)
        - Legal Opinions (Box 161)
        - Library (ONUC) (Box 161)
        - Lumumba, New York 1 August 1960 (Box 161)
        - Lumumba, Investigating Commission (Box 161)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Lumumba, Investigating Commission (cables) (Box 161)
        - Mercenaries (Box 161)
        - Military memos and reports (Box 161)
        - Monetary Council (Box 161)
        - Non combatants, loss of life and suffering (Box 161)
        - Operational Memos (Box 161)
        - Organization ONUC (Box 161)
        - Photographs (Box 161)
        - Policy Directives (Box 161)
        - Recaps (Box 161)
        - Red Cross (Box 161)
        - Refugees (Box 162)
        - Reports, miscellaneous (Box 162)
        - Security Council --info. sheet for Members (Box 162)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Sahbani Mission (cables) (Box 162)
        - South Kasai (Box 162)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Spinelli, Sudan (cables) (Box 162)
        - Miscellaneous files: (Box 162)
        - Staff, ONUC (Box 162)
        - Situation Reports (Box 162)
        - Secretariat Delegation to Congo (Box 162)
        - UN Fund for Congo (Box 162)
        - Weekly Reports (Box 162)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Correspondence files:
        - Misc. (Box 162)
        - Bunche (Box 162)
        - Dayal (Box 162)
        - de Seynes (Box 162)
        - Gordon, King (Box 162)
        - Labouisse (Box 162)
        - Linner (Box 162)
        - McKeown (Box 162)
        - Vaughan (Box 162)
      - Belgium (Vols. I and II) (Box 163)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Republic of the Congo (Vols. I, II, III) (Box 163)
      - (All Restricted) (Box 164)
      - Afghanistan (Box 164)
      - Argentina (Box 164)
      - Australia (Box 164)
      - Austria (Box 164)
      - Brazil (Box 164)
      - Burma (Box 164)
      - Cameroun (Box 164)
      - Canada (Box 164)
      - Central African Rep. (Box 164)
      - Ceylon (Box 164)
      - Chad (Box 164)
      - Chile (Box 164)
      - China (Box 164)
      - Congo (Brazzayille) (Box 164)
      - Czechoslovakia (Box 164)
      - Denmark (Box 164)
      - Ecuador (Box 164)
      - Ethiopia (Box 164)
      - Finland (Box 164)
      - France (Box 164)
      - Ghana (Box 165)
      - Greece (Box 165)
      - Guinea (Box 165)
      - Haiti (Box 165)
      - Hungary (Box 165)
      - India (Box 165)
      - Indonesia (Box 165)
      - Iran (Box 165)
      - Iraq (Box 165)
      - Ireland (Box 165)
      - Israel (Box 165)
      - Italy (Box 165)
      - Ivory Coast (Box 165)
      - Japan (Box 165)
      - Jordan (Box 165)
      - Liberia (Box 166)
      - Libya (Box 166)
      - Madagascar (Box 166)
      - Malaya (Box 166)
      - Mali (Box 166)
      - Mexico (Box 166)
      - Morocco (Box 166)
      - Nepal (Box 166)
      - Netherlands (Box 166)
      - New Zealand (Box 166)
      - Niger (Box 166)
      - Nigeria (Box 166)
      - Norway (Box 166)
      - Pakistan (Box 166)
      - Peru (Box 166)
      - Poland (Box 166)
      - Portugal (Box 166)
      - Saudi Arabia (Box 166)
      - Senegal (Box 166)
      - Sierra Leone (Box 166)
      - Somalia (Box 166)
      - South Africa (Box 166)
      - Spain (Box 166)
      - Sudan (Box 166)
      - Surinam (Box 166)
      - Sweden (Box 166)
      - Switzerland (Box 166)
      - Tanganyika (Box 167)
      - Togo (Box 167)
      - Tunisia (Box 167)
      - Uganda (Box 167)
      - USSR (Box 167)
      - UAR (Box 167)
      - UK (Box 167)
      - USA (Box 167)
      - Upper Volta (Box 167)
      - Venezuela (Box 167)
      - Yemen (Box 167)
      - Yugoslavia (Box 167)
      - (RESTRICTED) *Code cables, July 1960-February 1962 (Volumes I-XXI) (Box 168#-173#)
      - Advisory Committee: Verbatims of meetings, August-October 1960 (Box 174)
      - Advisory Committee: Verbatims of meetings Sept 1961-January 1962 (Box 174)
    - Sub-subseries V.5.4: Rang-Jensen Case
      - *(RESTRICTED) Administrative Tribunal: (Box 175#)
        - Application of Mr. Bang-Jensen, Case No. 80 (28 August 1958) (Box 175)
        - Application of Mr. Bang-Jensen, Annexes (Box 175)
        - Cordier file re questions asked by Bang-Jensen 21 November 1958 (Box 175)
      - Chronological set of papers on Bang-Jensen case 1957-1958 (7 volumes)--see itemized and numbered list in V.I. (V.I -III) (Box 175)
      - Chronological set of papers on Bang-Jensen case 1957-1958 (V.IV-VII) (Box 176#)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Correspondence Folder: (Box 177#)
        - Governments (Box 177#)